何
What is it?
Inbox
Sender: Yuki Funahara
Subject: Important
Dec. 24, 2112, 3:20
I have something  important
to talk to you about.
It may have something
to do with an MWPSB case.
I'd rather not talk on the phone or online.
It'll be quicker if you see it so I'm attaching a
map to the location. I'll be waiting...
It'll be quicker if you see it so
I'm attaching a map to the location.
I'll be waiting for you there
at 3 PM tomorrow."
at 3 PM tomorrow.
My head is overflowing with thoughts
I can't allow anyone to know about
誰にも見せられないもの
脑海里充斥着的喧嚣
頭の中溢れて
谁都无法看见
I've strayed into a world void of even mistakes
間違いさえも無い世界へ
我在这个不会犯错的机械世界里
迷い込んでる
一路行走一路彷徨
It's being rubbed in so deep it's hard to believe
あり得ないほど擦り込まれてる
与你擦肩而过的次数多到近乎异常
This "world" that holds
only what the eye can see
目に見えるものだけの“世界”現象
我眼里能看到的 就是我全部的世界
Can I flush out the truth?
暴きだせるかな
能否打破它
Plastic Tac Tic,
no one can go crazy anymore
Plastic Tac Tic
plastic tac tic
もう誰もおかしくなれないよ
所有人都习以为常
You, too, are in a plastic beautiful world
貴様もplastic beautiful world
你也一样 plastic beautiful world
In a world with too much beauty,
for some reason I can't see the light
美しすぎる世界に
在这个过于完美的世界里
僕はなぜか
我为什么
光が見えなくて
看不到光明的方向
My bursting heart is an eternal reflection
破裂していく心が
心在一步步碎裂
無限のリフレクション
回音无限
secret remains for you
为你留下这个秘密
Secret remains for you
Don't expose these false colors and futures
見せかけの色と
徒有其表的鲜艳色彩及未来
未来を暴かないで
别打破它
fake's plastic world
keep it secret motion
就让这个秘密继续秘密下去
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:草泥马 TMR@10 校对:西西   后期:时末
玛土撒拉的游戏
※玛土撒拉：希伯莱语圣经中最长寿的老人 其死亡寓意神对时代的审判
#10 Methuselah's Game
Yes. That email was
the last I heard from her.
はい　そのメールが最後で
Kaori says that she hasn't been able
to reach her since yesterday, either.
佳織も昨日から全然連絡がつかないって
Yes... Sure, yes. I'll contact you
right away if anything comes up.
はい…ええ　はい
何かあったらすぐに連絡します
Well then...
それじゃあ
So she didn't go back
to her parents' place, either?
実家にも戻ってないか
Seems like it.
そうみたいです
Any chance that she's playing a prank?
いたずらの可能性は
She often teases me, but she
wouldn't do something like this.
からかわれるのはしょっちゅうですけど
こんな悪質なことする子じゃありません
Well, actually going there
to check it out is our best shot.
まあ　行って確かめるのが一番だろうな
I'm sorry to drag you along on your day off.
すみません　非番なのに…
That's okay.
いいさ
Am I mixing personal and official business?
公私混同ですか　これって
It'll be all right as long
as Gino doesn't find out.
ギノに見つからなきゃ大丈夫さ
Is this friend of yours the type
who tends to come to this kind of place?
あんたの友達は　普段からこんな場所をうろつくタイプなのか
No way.
いいえ　そんな
It's a little strange, isn't it?
ちょっと変ですよね
It's definitely strange.
There's no doubt that this is a trap.
明らかに変だろ
間違いなくワナだ
You're being targeted.
あんた狙われてるぞ
I am? By who?
私が
誰に
Do you recall doing anything
to make any enemies?
恨みを買うような覚えは
No way I did!
あるわけないじゃないですか
Hey, you do realize
you're a detective, don't you?
やっぱりデカの自覚ないんじゃないのか
You're giving me that too?!
狡噛さんまで 何言ってんですか
In any case, I'll go check it out.
Just stay there and wait for me.
ともかく　俺が様子を見てくる
そこで待ってろ
But if this is really
a trap, you'll be in danger.
でも　ホントにワナなら危険です
That's exactly why. If we both get
taken out, who's gonna call for help?
だからだよ
２人揃ってやられたら 誰が助けを呼ぶ
Shouldn't we call for backup right away?
すぐに応援を呼ぶべきじゃないんですか
If you feel it's necessary, then do it.
あんたが必要と判断したらそうしろ
Also, give me permission to carry arms.
あと武装の許可を頼む
Ah... Okay.
はい
This is Akane Tsunemori.
On my authority as an Inspector,
常守朱　監視官権限により 執行官の武装を申請
I request permission
for an Enforcer to carry arms.
Voiceprint and ID confirmed.
声紋 ならびにＩＤを認証
Level 2 equipment use is granted.
レベル２装備を認可します
I'll leave the navigation to you.
ナビゲーションは任せる
You've got the location map, right?
ロケーションマップあるよな
Yes.
The data is old, but it's still usable.
データは古いですけど　一応は…
Do you see anyone there?
誰かいますか
No.
いいや…
In the back there...
その奥は…
Hey...
おい
In the back there, there's a dead end.
その奥は行き止まりです
Mr. Kogami...
狡噛さん…
Mr. Kogami? What? Wait... what's this?
狡噛さん
ちょっと…何これ
Hey... What's going on?
ちょっ…どういうこと
Hey, Inspector, what happened? Come in.
おい監視官 どうした　応答しろ
The reception is fine.
Please keep on going.
感度良好 そのまま進んでください
What the heck is this?
何だ　こいつは…
It's an abandoned subway line.
Please check the train cars.
破棄された地下鉄路線です
車両を捜索してください
Mr. Kogami! Can you hear me?! Come in!
狡噛さん　聞こえますか
応答して
Hey, Inspector! What's going on?!
おい監視官 何がどうなってる
It's an abandoned subway line.
Please check the train cars.
破棄された地下鉄路線です
車両を捜索してください
Don't worry. I'm an MWPSB detective.
安心しろ　公安局の刑事だ
Ah...
Who are you?
あんたは
I'm Yuki Funahara.
船原ゆきです
Are you a friend
of Akane Tsunemori?
常守朱の友人
You know Akane?!
朱を知ってるんですか
I'm one of her colleagues.
同僚だ
This isn't good. The basement is submerged.
駄目だな～ 地下室は水没している
From the smell, it's definitely
polluted water mixed with liquid waste.
臭いからして間違いなく廃液混じりの汚染水だ
If something like that gets poured on you,
you'll be in for a world of hurt.
あんなの生身で浴びたら 無事じゃ済まんぞ
But Mr. Kogami unmistakably
moved ahead beyond that point.
でも　間違いなく狡噛さんはその先に進んだんです
In fact, he went back even further,
going through the wall!
それどころか壁を通り抜けて　もっと奥まで
Isn't that a problem with the navigator?
ナビの故障じゃね
The issue might not be with
the hardware, but the software.
ハードじゃなく ソフトの問題かも…
Since this area has
been repeatedly redeveloped,
この辺は再開発を何度も繰り返してたから
you'd never know if the entered
data matches the actual condition.
登録されてるデータが実態どおりかどうか 知れたもんじゃないわ
Aren't you the only one who got deceived...
だまされたのは君だけじゃないのか
Inspector Tsunemori?
常守監視官
What?
Kogami left your surveillance
and his location is lost.
狡噛は君の監視下を離れ 位置情報もロスト
In other words...
つまり…
...he might've staged this situation
from the start in order to run away.
初めから逃亡をするもくろみで
この状況を演出したのかもしれん
Err... missy...
あ～お嬢ちゃん
Suppose we trust the navigator
instead of the map data.
取りあえずマップデータよりナビを信じるとしてだな
Do you know in which
direction Kogami was headed?
狡噛はどっちの方角に向かったか分かるか
Did the signal show any strange movements?
信号が妙な動きをしたりとかは
Come to think of it...
「妙な」っていえば…
...after a while, he suddenly started
moving in a straight line really fast.
途中からいきなりスーッと ものすごい速さで真っすぐに…
Oh, I see! He must be in some vehicle now.
そうだ　乗り物に乗ったんだ
Isn't there a subway line around here
that runs in a north-south direction?
この辺りに南北に走る地下鉄路線がありませんか
Hold on a sec.
ちょっと待って
There is.
あるわね
The subway Ginza Line.
地下鉄銀座線
But it was discontinued sixty years ago.
でも６０年前に廃線になってる
Then, it wasn't you who
sent Akane Tsunemori an email?
じゃあ　常守朱にメールを送ったのはあんたじゃないんだな
I don't know who did!
What's going on?
知らないわよ 何なのよこれ
What am I doing here?!
何で私こんな所にいるのよ
Someone captured you and brought you here.
あんたを捕まえて ここに連れてきたやつがいる
You don't remember anything?
何も覚えてないか
I don't know.
分からない…
After I finished working
overtime and got home,
ゆうべは残業片付けて帰ったら
I took a bath and went straight to bed.
お風呂入って ベッドに直行で…
When I woke up, I was already here.
目が覚めたらもうここにいたのよ
What's going on?
どういうこと
It seems you were used as
bait to lure Inspector Tsunemori.
あんたは常守監視官を釣るための餌にされたらしい
No...
いや…
...subway line.
Please investigate the train cars.
地下鉄路線です
車両を捜索してください
It's an abandoned subway line.
破棄された地下鉄路線です
Akane's voice?!
朱の声
It's well made, but it's a
fake created from voice samples.
よくできてるが サンプリングから合成した偽物だ
They knew all along that she wouldn't
be the one to come to the basement,
地下に入ってくるのは彼女じゃなくて 代理の誰かだと最初から予想していやがった
but someone else would instead.
Their target isn't Tsunemori.
目当ての獲物は常守じゃない
俺なのか
Are they after me?
Did it stop?
止まったの
I guess this means they want us to get off.
「降りろ」って意味かな
Where are we?
どこよ　ここ
They're jamming the signal.
電波妨害だな
It seems like they
want to isolate us at all costs.
どうあっても俺たちを孤立させたいらしい
They want us to go in here?
「ここへ入れ」ってことなの
It's annoying that we have
to do what they tell us to do, but...
言いなりになるのはしゃくだがな
Seems like we have no other choice.
どうやら選択の余地はないらしい
Follow me!
ついてこい
What's this place?!
何だ　ここは…
Things have been
going as we planned so far.
ここまでは予定どおり
It seems they're quick
to pick up on things, too.
向こうものみ込みが早いようだね
The smarter the prey,
the more enjoyable the hunt becomes.
獲物が賢いほど狩りも楽しくなる
That's good.
いいですね
Looks like it'll be a worthwhile
game to watch from the bleachers.
客席からも観戦しがいのあるゲームになりそうだ
Why don't you take part
in the hunt for a change?
君もたまには狩りに参加してみてはどうかね
My interest lies in what
will transpire during this hunt.
僕はここで起こる出来事 そのものに興味があるのでね
So it'd be best for me to
observe things as a third party.
第三者の視点で 観察するのが一番です
What are those?
それは
They're chemical lights.
ケミカルライトだ
Wouldn't the flashlight be better?
普通のライトの方がよくない
If you have a light source in your hand,
you'll be a good target in the dark.
光源を手に持っていれば 闇の中では格好の的だ
Also, it can serve as a sign that
you've already been down that path.
それに一度通った道の目印にもなる
So Akane's job is dangerous like this?
朱ってこんな危険な仕事を
It's gotten especially bad lately.
ここ最近は特にひどいな
I should've taken
her concerns more seriously.
もっと真剣に相談に乗ってあげればよかった
She works at the MWPSB.
公安局の人間だ
She can't discuss the
details of her work with civilians.
仕事の詳細は民間人には話せない
Is she doing okay at work?
職場ではうまくやってるの
She has...
あいつは…
...faith. She intuitively understands
what it means to be a detective.
信念を持ってる
デカっていうのはどういう仕事なのか
直感的に理解してる
I think the people society
really needs are people like her.
世の中に本当に必要なのは
ああいうタイプだと思う
She was different
even when we were in school.
学生のころから不思議な子だったよ
No matter what the trouble was,
once she intervened, it got resolved.
どんなもめ事も朱が間に入ると解決しちゃうの
I wonder if those people with
the clearest Psycho-Pass Hues
サイコパス色相がいっつも最高にクリアなのって
きっとああいうタイプばかりなのかな
are always people like her.
Ah... Is it possible that you're the
subordinate who puts her at a loss?
もしかして
朱を振り回している部下ってあなたのこと？
So that's how she talks about me?
俺のことをそういうふうに言ってたのか　あいつは…
What's the matter?
どうしたの
It's a trap.
ワナだ
Even their traps are anachronistic.
ワナまでアナクロだな
They've sure got interesting tastes.
いい趣味してるぜ
Ah... wait. A little to the right
of the floor you just checked...
待って さっきの床のちょっと右の方
That's the same bag we saw earlier!
さっきと同じバッグだよ
Don't!
よせ
I... I just saw someone!
今…今　人がいた
Yeah. Now I know what this is all about.
ああ　これで趣旨が見えた
They want to entertain
themselves with some fox hunting.
やつらキツネ狩りを楽しむ気だ
H-Hunting?
か…狩り
Those Drones are hunting dogs.
ドローンは猟犬役だ
When the prey gets frightened
and runs, the player finishes it off.
おびえて逃げた獲物をプレーヤーが仕留める
So we're the poor foxes.
俺たちは哀れなキツネ役ってわけさ
O-Oh no...
そ…そんな…
Don't panic. Don't be scared.
慌てるな　怖がるな
Calm down and look for the escape route.
落ち着いて慎重に逃げ道を探すんだ
The more we panic,
the more we play right into their hands.
焦れば焦るほど敵の思うつぼだ
Where's the bag you picked up earlier?
さっき拾ったバッグは
Th-This one?
これ
What's that?
何
It's a portable transponder.
携帯トランスポンダだな
We can communicate with this
even while they're jamming the signal.
これなら電波妨害の中でも通信できる
W-We can call for help?!
た…助けが呼べるの
Unfortunately, it's missing
the battery and antenna.
残念ながらバッテリーとそれにアンテナ素子がない
I'll distract them.
やつらの注意をそらす あんたはここに隠れてろ
You keep hiding here.
What're you gonna do?
どうするつもり
We have no chance
with two hunting dogs.
猟犬が２匹じゃ勝ち目はない
Unless I bring at
least one of them down...
せめて片方だけでも つぶさないと
...they'll surround us,
and that'll be the end of the road for us.
このまま囲まれておしまいだ
Oh?
Mr. Kogami!
狡噛さん
Run!
走れ
I killed one of them. And...
１台仕留めた　それに…
...all I need now is the antenna.
あとはアンテナだ
He sure is something else.
とんでもないやつだ
Though he may just be a fox,
that still makes him a canine.
キツネといえど イヌ科の獣です
Or, perhaps he's a member of the wolf family.
あるいはオオカミの眷属かもしれない
Makishima... Did you add in some
plot to this game unbeknownst to me?
槙島君　今回のゲームについて
さては何か私の知らない趣向まで組み込んでいるのかね
When a man faces fear, his soul is tested.
人は恐怖と対面したとき 自らの魂を試される
What he was born to seek...
What he was born to achieve...
何を求め　何を成すべくして生まれてきたか
His true nature will become clear.
その本性が明らかになる
Are you trying to mock me?
私をからかっているつもりかね
It's not just that Kogami guy.
あの狡噛という男だけではない
I'm interested in you, too, Mr. Senguji.
あなたにも興味があるんです　泉宮寺さん
An unforeseen situation...
An unexpected turn of events...
不測の事態予期せぬ展開を前にして
In the face of those,
you too will face your true self.
あなたもまた本当の自分と直面することになるでしょう
I know that is the thrill and
excitement you've been seeking.
そんなスリルと興奮を あなたは求めていたはずだ
Indeed.
いかにも
Well, I must say I don't really mind that
habit of yours of looking down on others.
君のそういう人を食ったところは
私も嫌いではないよ
Now, Shinya Kogami...
さて　狡噛慎也
Will you understand
the meaning of this game?
君はこの問いの意味を理解してくれるかな
I can't... run anymore.
もう駄目　走れない
I can't! I can't do it!
もう嫌…無理
Hey, are you listening?
ねえ　聞いてる
Sorry, but I'm in the middle
of thinking about something.
悪いが 考え事の最中だ
Just say something.
いいから何かしゃべって
When you're quiet,
you're kinda scary, so...
あんたって黙ってると何か怖いんだもん
I was thinking...
考えていた
With you as bait,
they lured in Tsunemori,
あんたを餌にして常守が釣られ
but they knew it was actually
me who'd go look for you instead.
代わりに俺が捜しに行くことまで織り込み済みで
They factored all that
in when setting up this hunt.
連中はこの狩りをセッティングした
It's you who they want to play with, right?
あいつらが遊びたいのはあんたなんでしょ
I'm just... Dammit!
私はただの… くそっ
I'm just being dragged into this, right?!
巻き添え食ってるだけなんでしょ
That's right. With regard to you,
そのとおりだ　あんたについては
your role should've been over when
your email was sent at the beginning.
最初の偽メールを仕掛けた時点で役目は終わっていたはずだ
And yet, why did they put you on the subway?
なのにやつらはどうしてあんたを地下鉄に乗せた
Isn't it...
それってさ
...to make it difficult for you to run away?
あんたが簡単に逃げられないようにするためじゃない
In fact, I'm holding you back like this now.
だって今もこうしてあんたの足引っ張ってる
If I weren't here, you'd have an
easier time running away, right?
私がいなければあんた一人でもっとうまく逃げてるんでしょ
It's fine. Do what you wanna do.
いいわよ　好きにしなさいよ
フッ　最低
This is terrible...
This fox hunt...
このキツネ狩り　ただのワンサイドゲームじゃない
...is not just a one-sided game.
They're hinting that
I've got a chance, too.
やつらは俺にも勝ち目があるとちらつかせてる
In other words, I'm being tested.
つまり　俺は試されてる
Whether I abandon
you during this game or not...
途中であんたを見捨てるか否か
I bet it's also one of the
keys to winning this game.
きっとそいつも勝敗を握る鍵の一つなんだ
Hey, take off your clothes!
おい　服を脱げ
Huh?! Wh-What're you
thinking in a place like this?!
何考えてんのよ　こんなとこで
Just give them to me.
いいから　よこせ
Are you insane?!
Have you lost it or something?!
あんた正気？頭でもいかれたの？
If you wanna survive, just do as I say!
生き残りたければ言うとおりにしろ
To think a perv like you is a MWPSB detective!
こんなド変態が公安の刑事だなんて
Wh-What're you looking at?!
な…何見てんのよ
Don't you usually
coordinate your underwear?
あんたは下着を揃えないのか
That's...
そんな…えっ？何で？
What?
Why?
Give me your underwear, too.
下着もよこせ
L-Look that way!
あっ…あっち向いてなさいよね
I see...
なるほどな
The last item needed to
beat the game was hidden on you.
攻略アイテムの最後の一つはあんたが隠し場所だったんだ
Here's the antenna for the transponder.
トランスポンダのアンテナだ
In this area, there's some pretty
heavy jamming, though the range is limited.
この辺り局所的だけど かなり強力なジャミングがかかってますね
Where's the source of the jamming?
妨害電波の発信源は
It's coming from the southwest.
南西の方角
But based on the map,
there shouldn't be anything in that section.
ただ　マップ上だとこの区画何もないはずです
Okay then. We'll set up a relay base here.
よし　ここに中継基地を設営する
Don't trust the map data.
マップデータは信用するな
Check every single gap thoroughly.
隙間という隙間をしらみつぶしに調べろ
Also, as soon as you find Kogami,
shoot him with the Dominator.
それと　狡噛は見つけしだいドミネーターで撃て
You don't have to warn him.
警告は必要ない
But we still don't
know for sure if he ran away!
でも　まだ脱走と決まったわけじゃ…
The Sibyl System will make that decision.
その判断はシビュラシステムが下す
If he didn't do anything wrong,
his Crime Coefficient will be the same.
狡噛にやましいところがなければ 犯罪係数にも変化はない
The Paralyzer mode will settle it.
パラライザーモードで決着はつく
If he really wanted to run,
マジに逃げる気だったんなら 容赦なくエリミネーターが起動しますよね
then it'll mercilessly
activate the Eliminator mode, right?
You can't fool the cymatic scan.
サイマティックスキャンはごまかせない
It'll show Kogami's real intentions.
それで狡噛の本心も分かる
Are you saying that it's okay to kill him?!
殺しても構わないっていうんですか
You used to be his friend, right?!
宜野座さん　友達だったんでしょ
If he ends up dying...
これで狡噛が死ぬはめになれば
Inspector Tsunemori, the fault will
lie on you due to your poor supervision.
常守監視官　全ては君の監督責任だ
If you had Kogami under control,
君がちゃんと狡噛をコントロールしていれば
this wouldn't have had to happen.
こんな事態にはならなかったんだ
How do you feel about someone
dying because of your own incompetency?
どうだ？自らの無能で人が死ぬ気分は
Hey, Inspector...
なぁ　監視官
How about you stop right there?
That was a little too sinister.
それくらいにしとこうか
ちょっと陰険過ぎるぜ
It's from Kogami!
狡噛からです
You can detect my location, right?
こっちの位置が探知できるな？現在コード１０８が進行中
A Code 108 is currently in progress.
Send in reinforcements immediately.
至急応援を！繰り返す…
I repeat.
- Send in all the Drones we've got!
- A Code 108 is currently in progress.
Send in reinforcements immediately.
ありったけのドローンを急行させろ
でも経路が…
But we don't know what path to take.
Try randomly!
手当たり次第に試せ
Make sure at least one Drone reaches him!
１台でもいいから到着させるんだ
Mr. Kogami...
狡噛さん　間に合って！
Let us make it in time!
Looks like the fairy tale died a moment ago
御伽話（フェアリーテイル）は
童话般的美好
さっき死んだみたい
在刚刚已经死去
煉瓦の病棟で
瓦墙下的病房
In a hospital ward made of bricks,
I found it hard to sing
うまく歌えなくて
在这里我无法歌唱
霧に煙る夜
灰灰蒙蒙的夜
Red moon, come out on this foggy night
浮かべ赤い月
悬浮飘红的月
ほらみて　私を
快 看我
Now look at me, don't avert your gaze
目を逸らさないで
别移开你的视线
I was born behind black iron bars
黒い鉄格子の中で
黑黑的铁栅背后
私は生まれてきたんだ
我来到这个世界
悪意の代償を願え
祈祷恶的代价
Wish for payback for the evil done
望むがままにお前に
如你所愿给你吧
As you wish, I'll give you your justice
さあ与えよう正義を
给与你
Before you destroy and get destroyed
壊して　壊される前に
破坏掉正义 在自身毁灭之前
因果の代償を払い
付出因果的代价
Pay karma's price, and let's go together
共に行こう
一起走吧
Monster without a name
名前のない怪物
无名怪兽
A world where humans' state of mind and the tendency of their
personalities can be quantified. While all sorts of inclinations
are recorded and policed, these measured numbers
used to judge people's souls are commonly called "Psycho-Pass."
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations that appear in the show
are fictitious and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.